Eslam Mohamed Moemen

Maadi, Cairo

eslammoemen@icloud.com

****01002389382



in linkedin.com/in/eslammoemen

Summary

A Mobile Developer with experience in analysis, design, development, implementation and testing. Specialize in developing applications for the iOS platform with rich and intuitive GUI. Solid background of computer science and practical programming skills. a self-motivated, quick learner and a good team player.

- Well knowledge of Swift interoperability in the iOS ecosystem
- Designed Apps using iOS software patterns like MVC, MVVM, Viper
- Well Understanding of SOLID principles and implementing them in large scale projects
- Practiced one or more CI/CD Pipeline plurality such as Xcode Cloud and Github Actions, Fastlane
- Integrated Mutable Contents in Notification Service Extensions with APNS and firebase
- Solid Knowledge of Apple iOS Coordinator System and AutoLayout
- Implemented iOS Deep Linking With Apple Associated Domains and URL Scheme
- · Senior RESTful API Integration with Codable Protocol and swift Generics and operated GraphQl using Apollo Kit

Most Popular Projects

ECommerce APP

e-commerce app is a general platform for creating and generating multi vendor apps like pharmacies, stores, cloth shops, malls etc.

Related Links

taqwa foods: https://testflight.apple.com/join/KLk4tLwN i7-store:https://testflight.apple.com/join/1DblOXnn cityRolls-store: https://testflight.apple.com/join/aevrkpEB

Experience



Senior iOS Developer

Codes Roots

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Supervising ECommerce iOS App Which Serving any Vendor Registration as SAAS and Designing its base Architecture With Multi Flavor iOS Concept which using .xcconfig files for each Sandbox and Production

- Leading, Supporting and contributing Functional Team
- Building Architecture for Large Scale Multi-flavor SaaS Software
- enhance Prototype Existence using CI/CD and automation for Deployment and Store Releases



iOS Engineer

Codes Roots

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Created, Modified and Managed SATA System which Consists of 3 iOS Native Apps SATA Food(Services as Talabat), Delivery, Vendor and SATA Go App (Services as inDriver)

- implemented Food ,Go App in VIPER Architecture with Error Module Handler
- Connected Apps With Socket I.O and Web Socket as a live Order Cycle

iOS Engineer

Icosol Smart Technologies

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022 (4 months)

Responsible for Designing and Implementing Physio App

- Creating and Designing App From Scratch
- · Contributing with Back-end team to
- used MVVM Binding as a Design Architecture
- Applied SOLID Principles with Clean Code Concept
- Integrated Push Notifications with firebase



iOS Engineer

EndPoint Software Solutions

Jun 2018 - Jan 2022 (3 years 8 months)

Designed and Developed Many Apps from Scratch and Uploaded them as a Software House Provider ,it contained medium functionality focused on business or consumer software.

- · Designed All with iOS Patterns MVC, MVVM
- · Included Source Control Git with GitHub
- Implemented Push Notifications with Firebase Cloud Messaging
- Implemented more then once Google Maps and Apple MapKit



iOS Developer

MYA Health Care

Jan 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

- Developed and uploaded existing Project of Clinics and Appointment Reservations to the App-Store
- Created and Integrated Apple Push Notification Certificates with Firebase Cloud Messaging

Education



Minufiya University

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences, General 2015 - 2019

Skills

MVVM Binding • Git • Spatial Reasoning • Research Skills • Project Management • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • iOS Development • Data Structures • Design Patterns • iOS